I I need to hear a little bit about, you
know, your personal story. I mean, in
addition to you being being extremely
knowledgeable and also plugged in with
DC and having the angle of CIA, which we
really didn't even dive into all that
stuff, definitely have to have you back.
I mean, you saw some really pivotal
parts of of of American history where
you were on the lines, you were in
Pakistan, you saw that torture program.
You mentioned that Cheney was in that
room there and then I guess you saw kind
of the things that went into place.
Maybe I start there. What was Cheney
like then when you were in when you were
in Pakistan kind of what happened and
then how did that lead to you being in
prison? Because that's that's a serious
thing to happen to someone.
Uh, the first question is the easiest
one. Cheney was a mean, cold,
sociopathic son of a Uh, nothing
at all like George W. Bush. Bush was
warm and friendly. Not terribly bright,
but the nicest guy in the world. I
remember going to a briefing at the
White House and the guy that I went with
was was very portly
and um and he had a
he had a kind of a handlebar mustache
and and the president made a a joke
about the mustache and he said, "I see
you've got I forget exactly what he
said. I see you've got a a so and so
thing going." and he he alluded to some
entertainer and my friend said, "Uh,
actually, I think I've got a I've got a
uh
William Howard Taft thing going." I had
to think about the president because he
was so fat. You know, these stories that
William Howard Taft got stuck in a
bathtub and it took six men to pull them
out. It's probably not true, but this is
the story in history. And W laughed to
the point where like I thought like
water was going to squirt out of his
nose or something. And Cheney just stood
there like a statue. Uh Cheney was a
liar, uh a manipulator. When he wasn't
getting the intelligence that he wanted
from the CIA, he just had the defense
department create its own intelligence
through Ahmed Chelvi and the Iraqi
National Congress. They just made it up.
The CIA said repeatedly that there were
no weapons of mass destruction. and
Cheney insisted that no, there were and
the CIA just hadn't found them. So, the
Iraqi National Congress and Ahmed Talib
said there were, so we're going to war
for that. Um, Cheney Cheney, you know, I
can't believe Cheney is still alive,
too, with all the health problems that
he's had. But he was just
one of the most despicable figures I've
ever encountered in in government.
Now, after 911, literally everybody at
CIA headquarters volunteered to go to
Afghanistan and fight. And my Arabic was
absolutely perfect at the time, fluent.
I was very proud of my Arabic language
skills. And uh I volunteered repeatedly
to go and they just wouldn't send me.
And I was enraged.
And uh it turned out that they wouldn't
send me because I only found out
accidentally. I ran into a buddy of mine
who was this legendary figure, Billy
Wah. Billy was a contractor, but he had
won something like 13 or 14 Purple
Hearts uh over the course of three wars.
And um and there was this period about
six weeks that I I just didn't see him.
He just vanished. And I ran into him in
the hall and I said, "Hey, Billy, where
you been?" And he whispers, "I've been
in Afghanistan." I said, "Yeah, what are
you doing in Afghanistan?"
And he looks at me like I'm crazy. And
he says, "I've been killing people. What
do you think I've been doing?" And it
dawned on me that that's why they
haven't sent me to Afghanistan. They
don't need linguists. They're not like
debriefing anybody. They're just killing
them. So I went into the office of the
deputy director for counterterrorism who
was an old buddy of mine and I said,
"Listen, if you don't send me to
Afghanistan right now, I am walking
straight to Exxon and I am not looking
back." And he's like, "All right, take
it easy. Can you go to Pakistan?" I
said, "Yes." when? He said, "Tomorrow."
I said, "Yes." "What do you want me to
do?" He said, "I want you to be chief of
counterterrorism operations." I said,
"Done. Let me just go home and pack."
And he said, "Okay." So, I called my
girlfriend who later became my wife. She
she was also a senior CIA officer. I
said, "I got to go to Pakistan." She
said, "When? Tomorrow."
She goes, "Okay, I I'll help you pack."
She met me at my apartment and the next
morning I went to Pakistan and all hell
broke loose.
What do you mean by all hell broke
loose?
>> Oh, I came up with this idea. I'm very
proud to say we we had officers like
individual officers all the way up and
down the the US Pakistan border. And I
said, you know, this is so this is so
inefficient for us to have all these
people just out in the wilderness on the
top of these mountains hoping that some
al-Qaeda guy is going to be coming up
the path, you know, and he he grabs
them. I said, "Let's pull everybody off
the border, bring them into Pakistan,
let the bad guys come into Pakistan.
They'll end up in some safe house
someplace." And you know they're going
to make a mistake. They always make a
mistake and then we grab them. So that's
what we did. We pulled everybody off the
border. Of course, thousands, hundreds,
whatever it was, of al-Qaeda fighters
come into the country. They all go in
these safe houses and what do they do?
They immediately get on their cell phone
and we're like, "Thank you. Thank you,
NSA, for the tip." 2 o'clock in the
morning, we bust down the door and we
just grab we grabbed more people than we
knew what to do with. It was hundreds
and hundreds of al-Qaeda fighters. And
we got to the point very quickly where
the the Pakistani brigadier general that
I was working with most closely said to
me one night, "Listen, we filled the
jail there. There's no more room, not
for one more guy. You got to do
something with these guys." So I called
headquarters and I said the packs are
telling me that the jail's full. We we
were putting them in Raul Pindi jail
because it was centrally located just
outside of uh of Islamabad.
And I said the jail is full. We got to
get rid of these guys. What do you want
me to do with them? And they said um put
them on a C12 and send them to
Guantanamo.
And I said Guantanamo, Cuba.
And they said yeah. I said, "Why in the
world would we send him to Cuba?" And
they said, 'Well, we came up with this
idea. We send him to Cuba until we can
decide which federal district district
to try them in. Either either Boston,
New York, Washington, or uh Eastern
District of Virginia, and then we divide
them up and send them to the districts
for trial. I said, "Oh, that's a great
idea." Okay. So, we had like a fleet of
C12s that would just come in, land, we
load these guys on in handcuffs, and
then they take off and they would all go
to Guantanamo. And as it turned out, you
know, as they were arriving and
populating Guantanamo, which got up to
over 700 people at one point, Dick
Cheney said, "You know what? Let's not
send them to those federal districts."
And that's how Guantanamo became
Guantanamo.
But the way I made a real name for
myself at the agency in addition to just
blind luck in some of these raids um was
the capture of Abu Zuba who was the
number three we believed at the time was
the number three in in al-Qaeda. He
wasn't the number three but he was a
very bad man and um he was the very
first high-V value target that that we
were able to locate and find. uh we had
killed Muhammad Atiff who had been the
the director of military affairs for
al-Qaeda. We we were able to drone him
to death in in Tora Bora. But but uh Abu
Za was the first one we took alive and
um and catching him that night literally
changed the course of the rest of my
life. My life was never the same. For
better, for worse,
mostly for worse. So Jim Rickards has
just recorded a video that's [music] not
available to anyone in the public. And
he's going to be talking about how this
upcoming recession is going to be fast.
[music] It's going to be bloody. It's
going to be nasty. But at the same time,
he's going to show you how you can
position yourself to profit from all of
this chaos. Now, we've made this [music]
video only available to our viewers. Go
to londonreal.tv/jim.
Watch that [music] immediately. I can't
say enough good things about Jim
Rickards. He understands the global
economic [music] system better than any
guest I've ever had on London Real. His
predictions are almost [music] uncannily
true, and you can learn how to profit
from his vision, from his expertise, and
his [music] understanding of economics.
So, go to lunderreal.tv/jim
or click the link below. It's an
excellent, [music] excellent look on
what's going to happen in the future and
how you can position yourself to profit
[music] from that. Jim is one of the
best in the business, one of my favorite
guests on London Real, and he's very,
very good at predicting the future and
showing us all to profit from it. So,
click the link, and I hope you enjoy.
Hey, do you want to profit from crypto?
[music] Then join my DeFi Academy. The
Crypto DeFi Academy will help you create
generational wealth. But don't [music]
take my word for it. Listen to my
students.
>> When I first got into crypto, I remember
thinking to myself, I need to learn
more.
Ryan Rose, learning crypto, learning
DeFi. Got to do it.
>> I am so grateful that I jumped in and
did this. I had to break through some
limiting beliefs that I can do this,
that I can afford this, that I can be in
this.
>> It challenges um the [music] things that
are deeply rooted within us.
>> Joining Defi Academy has been one of the
best decisions I have made on my
blockchain journey.
>> This course was a lifecher, a game
changer, a huge eye openener. coming
from knowing practically nothing at the
speed of the learning over the over 4
weeks was just fantastic.
>> The information you provided in this
class was invaluable. [music]
>> I feel far more confident in my next
steps.
>> You took complex concepts and made them
easier to understand. What's different
than so many other ones [music] is it
just doesn't tell you what to do. It
actually makes you do it.
>> This is for people who are serious about
becoming traders. This is the way it
should be done.
>> I realized from this learning experience
again that it is not about what you
learn but about who you learn it from.
>> The energy was insane. I' I've never
experienced such incredible energy on a
live call. Brian Rose, you you are a
legend, my friend.
>> It's the only thing in the market where
you can get all information and learn
everything what you need to know.
>> Everything is so clear and so well done.
and I am um just forever grateful for
this program.
>> It made me feel so much more confident
about crypto than I did before. [music]
>> I did not anticipate how passionate I
was going to become about it.
>> That's also been like a big learning
experience for me, not just in the
crypto space, but just an overall uh
balance of life.
>> What I've learned is, you know, how to
take ownership, you know, of my life in
a way that um I really I really hadn't
before. Yeah, you can't put a price on
that really.
>> I would recommend it to anybody. Top
notch.
>> Excellence does not come cheap, you
know. So, if you want excellence, you
got to pay for it. But it's so worth it.
>> Pull the trigger. That's what this
course is about.
>> You're not going to regret it. Really,
it's amazing.
>> Thank you, Brian and team.
>> So, what are you waiting for? Crypto is
happening now. Click the link below,
submit your application, and let me
mentor you on how to create generational
wealth and build the decentralized
financial infrastructure of the future.